hello today we're going to talk about
the invention of coca-cola America's
favorite soft drink so like in the
1800's John Pemberton was trying to make
patent medicines basically they were
fake medicines and most of them were
just like herbal hoozy ones who even
cares he was just trying to make
anything that would sell he was like I
want to make a fake medicine that made
women think that they'll never be
nervous or have farts and make men think
that they can be smarter so he decided
to use a new ingredient coca coca is
from a plant the South Americans would
chew it and be like we had so much
energy we weren't even hungry and we
hiked the whole Andes but really they
were just on cocaine John Pemberton was
like oh I should put this into my new
potion that I'm making and basically he
copied someone else's recipe called like
VIN Mariani it was like well I have a
wine I put coca in there a little of
this Cola in the Kola nut released a
little bit of caffeine and
he basically it was like what I give you
is a wine with cocaine caffeine then
people in Atlanta were like no nobody
can sell alcohol because of temperance
he was like okay well fine I'll just
make a temperance beverage he went back
into his laboratory and he decided to
just put the coca and the Kola together
but they were super bitter without the
wine so he added a ton of sugar and then
he made it into like a drink you know he
thought oh well people will love this it
wasn't like he was like I made a soda
because nobody even had that yet he had
a friend named Frank Robinson who was
like okay we'll I'll help you to sell
your medicine soda drink thingy first of
all you should change the k' in the
kola' to a c and and just call it what
it is coca-cola and the two c''s will
look really nice next to each other and
who wouldn't love that so they would
just advertise coca-cola as a medicine
for your brain they would say it's
invigorating and stimulating and healthy
for your nervous system using the exotic
extract of the coca and Kola nut to make
you super alive and ready to face your
day the first year he only sold 25
gallons
twenty-five thousand or twenty four
twenty five gallons okay in a year he
gave it to pharmacies they had like soda
fountains and fun things and people did
like it a lot
oh this is a great drink they thought
that it made them like invigorated and
aware people are basically drinking
little cocaine and soda
mimimi mimimi mimimi I need more I wish
I was alive than to drink the coke coke
coca-cola oh god I missed so much from
not being in the olden times
[Music]
the next year just hold 200 gallons a
month then throw much more 12 months
[Music]
Freddie stop it 12 branchy god dammit
hold on
ok I got 12 months out of the year we
sold 2,000 gallons a month no yes
god damn he's on his deathbed dying of
stomach cancer and he's like out of all
of the patent medicines that I've tried
to make I finally made a successful
patent medicine but what he never knew
was that he actually made the most
successful drink that humans will ever
drink ever party was so successful and
he doesn't know and he'll never know
ever they still use coca leaves in
modern-day coca-cola so do the math on
that one even if they don't have cocaine
and them they still use the leaves and
they took the cocaine out putting it
somewhere else
you